<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>urban mobility on</title><link>https://pintergreg.github.io/dissertation/tags/urban-mobility/</link><description>Recent content in urban mobility on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pintergreg.github.io/dissertation/tags/urban-mobility/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Commuting Analysis of the Budapest Metropolitan Area Using Mobile Network Data</title><link>https://pintergreg.github.io/dissertation/publications/pinter2022commuting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pintergreg.github.io/dissertation/publications/pinter2022commuting/</guid><description>by: Gergő Pintér and Imre Felde
abstract: The analysis of human movement patterns based on mobile network data makes it possible to examine a very large population cost-effectively and has led to several discoveries about human dynamics. However, the application of this data source is still not common practice. The goal of this study was to analyze the commuting tendencies of the Budapest Metropolitan Area using mobile network data as a case study and propose an automatized alternative approach to the current, questionnaire-based method, as commuting is predominantly analyzed by the census, which is performed only once in a decade in Hungary.</description></item><item><title>Awakening City: Traces of the Circadian Rhythm within the Mobile Phone Network Data</title><link>https://pintergreg.github.io/dissertation/publications/pinter2022awakening/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pintergreg.github.io/dissertation/publications/pinter2022awakening/</guid><description>by: Gergő Pintér and Imre Felde
abstract: In this study, call detail records (CDR), covering Budapest, Hungary, are processed to analyze the circadian rhythm of the subscribers. An indicator, called wake-up time, is introduced to describe the behavior of a group of subscribers. It is defined as the time when the mobile phone activity of a group rises in the morning. Its counterpart is the time when the activity falls in the evening.</description></item></channel></rss>