<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>human mobility on</title><link>/tags/human-mobility/</link><description>Recent content in human mobility on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/human-mobility/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Commuting Analysis of the Budapest Metropolitan Area Using Mobile Network Data</title><link>/publications/pinter2022commuting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publications/pinter2022commuting/</guid><description>by: Gergő Pintér and Imre Felde
abstract: The analysis of human movement patterns based on mobile network data makes it possible to examine a very large population cost-effectively and has led to several discoveries about human dynamics. However, the application of this data source is still not common practice. The goal of this study was to analyze the commuting tendencies of the Budapest Metropolitan Area using mobile network data as a case study and propose an automatized alternative approach to the current, questionnaire-based method, as commuting is predominantly analyzed by the census, which is performed only once in a decade in Hungary.</description></item><item><title>Awakening City: Traces of the Circadian Rhythm within the Mobile Phone Network Data</title><link>/publications/pinter2022awakening/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publications/pinter2022awakening/</guid><description>by: Gergő Pintér and Imre Felde
abstract: In this study, call detail records (CDR), covering Budapest, Hungary, are processed to analyze the circadian rhythm of the subscribers. An indicator, called wake-up time, is introduced to describe the behavior of a group of subscribers. It is defined as the time when the mobile phone activity of a group rises in the morning. Its counterpart is the time when the activity falls in the evening.</description></item><item><title>Analyzing the Behavior and Financial Status of Soccer Fans from a Mobile Phone Network Perspective: Euro 2016, a Case Study</title><link>/publications/pinter2021analyzing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publications/pinter2021analyzing/</guid><description>by: Gergő Pintér and Imre Felde
abstract: In this study, Call Detail Records (CDRs), covering Budapest, for the month of June in 2016 has been analyzed. During this observation period, the 2016 UEFA European Football Championship took place, which affected significantly the habit of the residents, despite the fact that not a single match was played in the city. We evaluated the fans&amp;rsquo; behavior in Budapest, during and after the Hungarian matches, and found that the mobile phone network activity reflects the football fans&amp;rsquo; behavior, demonstrating the potential of mobile phone network data within a social sensing system.</description></item><item><title>Evaluating the Effect of the Financial Status to the Mobility Customs</title><link>/publications/pinter2021evaluating/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publications/pinter2021evaluating/</guid><description>by: Gergő Pintér and Imre Felde
abstract: In this article, we explore the relationship between cellular phone data and housing prices in Budapest, Hungary. We determine mobility indicators from one month of Call Detail Records (CDR) data, while the property price data are used to characterize the socioeconomic status at the Capital of Hungary. First, we validated the proposed methodology by comparing the Home and Work locations estimation and the commuting patterns derived from the cellular network dataset with reports of the national mini census.</description></item></channel></rss>