<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docs on</title><link>/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Docs on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Analyzing the Mobility Customs of the Urban Population using Mobile Network Data</title><link>/docs/dissertation/preface/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/dissertation/preface/</guid><description>Ph.D. dissertation by Gergő Pintér
Supervisor: Dr. habil. Imre Felde
Date of the Defense #
July 7, 2022
Members of the Defense Committee #
Chair of the Committee
Prof. Dr. habil. József Tar, DSc (Óbuda University) Secretary
Dr. habil. Sándor Szénási, PhD (Óbuda University) Opponents
Prof. Dr. Róbert Fullér, DSc (Széchenyi István University) Prof. Dr. János Kertész, DSc, Member of the Hungarian Academy of Science (Central European University) Members
Dr. Tamás Tettamanti, PhD (Budapest University of Technology and Economics) Dr.</description></item><item><title>Abstract</title><link>/docs/dissertation/abstract/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/dissertation/abstract/</guid><description>Mobile phones are now fundamental parts of our life; they are practically always with us, wherever we go, almost as if they were a part of our body. The continuous communication between a device and the mobile networks leaves traces of our whereabouts in the operator&amp;rsquo;s system. In the last few decades, this information source has become a standard way of analyzing the characteristics of human mobility. During my research, I have analyzed Call Detail Records (CDR), covering Budapest, Hungary, and the surrounding settlements.</description></item><item><title>1. Introduction</title><link>/docs/dissertation/introduction/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/dissertation/introduction/</guid><description>Background #
Mobile phones are now fundamental parts of our life; they are practically always with us, wherever we go, almost as if they were a part of our body. The continuous communication between a device and the mobile networks leaves traces of our whereabouts in the operator&amp;rsquo;s system. Via these devices, the mobile network can &amp;ldquo;sense&amp;rdquo; our movements, which is the basis of the &amp;ldquo;Smart City&amp;rdquo; concept [1].
In the last few decades, anonymized Call Detail Records (CDR) have become a common information source for analyzing the characteristics of human mobility.</description></item><item><title>2. Literature Review</title><link>/docs/dissertation/literature_review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/dissertation/literature_review/</guid><description>Understanding human movements and recognizing behavior patterns that occur during daily life in urban areas requires a systematic analysis of that human mobility. The evaluation of human travel is based on observations on the individual and group levels. In the last decades, several novel datasets, based on vehicular GPS and cellular network records or social media information, became available, which provided more accurate and sophisticated characterization of people&amp;rsquo;s movements. This chapter provides a brief introduction to this field.</description></item><item><title>3. Data Sources</title><link>/docs/dissertation/data_sources/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/dissertation/data_sources/</guid><description>In this chapter, the data sets used in this research are described. The &amp;ldquo;April 2017&amp;rdquo; (Section Vodafone April 2017) and the &amp;ldquo;June 2016&amp;rdquo; (Section Vodafone June 2016) CDR data sets are described, along with other sources like the estate price data (Section Estate Price Data). Unless otherwise indicated, the CDR data denotes the &amp;ldquo;April 2017&amp;rdquo; data set through this work.
Vodafone April 2017 #
The CDR data were collected from Budapest, the capital of Hungary, and the surrounding county.</description></item><item><title>4. Data Processing Framework</title><link>/docs/dissertation/data_processing_framework/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/dissertation/data_processing_framework/</guid><description>A computational framework has been developed to process the CDR data, including preprocessing, cleaning, home and work location estimation, or calculating the mobility indicators (like Radius of Gyration and Entropy). This simplified process can be seen in Figure 4.1 and will be discussed further in this chapter.
Figure 4.1.: The simplified processing the Mobile Phone data along with the Cell information and the Estate Price data used to determine the financial status of the subscribers.</description></item><item><title>5. Social Sensing</title><link>/docs/dissertation/social_sensing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/dissertation/social_sensing/</guid><description>Social sensing is an application of the mobile network data (or social media) that utilizes humans as sensor carriers via wearable devices (like smartphones or smartwatches) in order to observe the situational awareness of the physical world [133]. I like to use the term, more specifically, when a social event or phenomenon is observed by the people&amp;rsquo;s attendance. I reviewed applications, falling into this category, from the literature in Section Social Sensing and COVID-19.</description></item><item><title>6. Commuting</title><link>/docs/dissertation/commuting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/dissertation/commuting/</guid><description>Hungary is a typical capital-oriented country. Budapest is the political, economic, logistical, and cultural center of the country, where almost 18% of the population lived [118]. In 2017, the population of Budapest was 1749734, and the population of Pest county was 1247372. In the agglomeration of Budapest, 837532 people lived according to KSH [142]. The river Danube divides the city into the Buda (Boo-da) and the Pest (Pesh-t) side. The former is the supposed more fashionable area, and the property values are remarkably higher (see Figure 3.</description></item><item><title>7. Awakening City</title><link>/docs/dissertation/awakening_city/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/dissertation/awakening_city/</guid><description>A mobile phone activity precisely follows the subscribers&amp;rsquo; daily routines. It is enough to see the daily periodicity in Figure 3.3a. As the daytime activity is so clearly distinguished from the nighttime activity, the question has arisen: &amp;ldquo;When does the day exactly begin?&amp;rdquo;. And a set of follow-up questions along with it: When do the inhabitants awaken? Are there any differences between the given type of subscribers? When does the city awaken?</description></item><item><title>8. Socioeconomic Status</title><link>/docs/dissertation/socioeconomic_status/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/dissertation/socioeconomic_status/</guid><description>In this chapter, the relations between mobility indicators and measures of socioeconomic status are explored. I have used two different approaches to characterize socioeconomic status: a more direct and a more indirect one. The latter is the housing price. As I demonstrated in Chapter Commuting, the home location estimation is reliable. When the home location of a subscriber is known, the typical housing price of that area can be associated with the subscriber, considering that if someone lives in a more expensive area, their socioeconomic status is higher.</description></item></channel></rss>